Nima Karami

REACT DEVELOPER | FRONT-END DEVELOPER | DESIGNER | FINANCE ENTHUSIAST | RECREATIONAL ATHLETE

SUMMARY

React and Javascript developer based in Toronto, Canada. Nima comes from a design and architecture background with 6+ years of experience which has granted him excellent communication and problemsolving skills.

Throughout his practice, Nima has always been a strong advocate for the use oftechnology; he coded as a hobby and held educational workshops in university passing his programming knowledge to fellow designers.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Address

Toronto, Canada

CONTACT

- nkarami.dev@gmail.com
- +1-437-234-6331
- nima-karami.github.io
- in nima-karami
- nima-karami

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Developer

FREELANCE

Apr 2021 - Present

- + Built and **deployed** a fully functional **face-recognition web app** using **React.js**, **express.js**, and Clarifai **REST API**. Created **session management** with **authentication routes** and **stored** user information with **hashed passwords** securely on a **PostgreSQL** database.
- + Developed a single-page portfolio website for a professional client using **React JS**, **Tailwind CSS**, and **React Router**.

UI/UX Designer | Frontend Developer

FUNCTIONLAND

May 2021 - May 2022

- + Designed and wireframed an innovative customer-centric **user interface** for fx.land website using **Figma** and **Photoshop**.
- + Managed and supervised a team of three designers for the production of the media content in an agile environment.
- + Collaborated with the front-end development team to implement the website using Svelte.

Architectural Staff

DIAMOND SCHMITT

Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

- + Utilized an **evolutionary algorithm** to **optimize** tower placement and geometry. This increased the gross floor area by approximately **12 percent**.
- + **Automated** the building shadow impacts analysis and **simulation** reports generation process, reducing the time required from **32 hours to 2 hours**.
- + Developed an **algorithm** to maximize daylight access while minimizing heat loss in high-rise residential buildings.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

Sep 2018 - Oct 2020

- + Managed and Instructed a class of 70+ students both in-person and remotely.
- + **Communicated** complex topics such as tension, flexural, and compression members using calculations, design aids, rules of thumb, and the latest CSA design standards.

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

FACULTY OF ENGINEERING | MARCH

Sep 2018 - Oct 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React	Javo	ascript	НТ	ML5	CS	S3	Redu	IX	SQL	N	oSQL	No	ode.js	Ex	pre	ess.js
Bootstra	ıp I	Material (Pytho	on	Nui	тру	Po	Pandas		Matplotlib		Pineso			Git

DESIGN SKILLS

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe InDesign Figma Rhinoceros 3D

Grasshopper 3D